Anton Mazzanovich Papers, 1885-1934, (bulk 1924-1934)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Anton Mazzanovich Papers,
1885-1934,
1924-1934
AZ 015
Mazzanovich, Anton
The collection contains correspondence, diary, newspaper clippings, articles, theater programs, photographs, and other materials relating to Anton Mazzanovich's experiences in Arizona and New Mexico, and his theatrical activities in New York. The materials date from 1885-1934, with the bulk of materials dating from 1924 through 1934.
1.25 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Anton Mazzanovich was an author, soldier, and thespian; he served with Troop F, 6th Cavalry, 1881-1882, in Arizona and New Mexico. Anton was also a stage carpenter and mechanic with New York theater companies.nton Mazzanovich was an author, soldier, and thespian; he served with Troop F, 6th Cavalry, 1881-1882, in Arizona and New Mexico. Anton was also a stage carpenter and mechanic with New York theater companies.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 5 sereis
Series I: Correspondence, 1916-1917, 1924-1934.
Series II: Newspaper clippings, 1925-1934.
Series III: Patents, 1897-1925.
Series IV: Theater materials, 1885-1920.
Series IV: Manuscripts
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, diary, newspaper clippings, articles, theater programs, photographs, and other materials relating to Mazzanovich's experiences in Arizona and New Mexico, and his theatrical activities in New York. Includes the original typescript of a projected work, Southwest Frontier; material relating to his book, Trailing Geronimo, 1926; and several U.S. patents obtained by Mazzanovich for stage and scenery construction, bottles, and streetcars. Theater materials include playbills, programs, and a diary from his 1891-92 theater season tour. Photographs are reprints accumulated for use in Southwest Frontier and are early views of Arizona and New Mexico towns, Apache Indians, Fort Grant, and army life.
Access Terms
Horn, Tom, 1860-1903.
Clum, John P., 1851-1932.
Geronimo, 1829-1909.
United States. Army. Cavalry, 6th.
United States. Army -- Military life -- History.
Frontier and pioneer life.
Southwest, New.
Apache Indians -- Wars.
Apache Indians -- Photographs.
Theater -- United States.
Cities and towns -- Arizona -- History -- Photographs.
Arizona -- History, Local -- Photographs.
Arizona -- History, Local -- Photographs.
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1916-1917; 1924-1934
  - Correspondence, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - United Indian War Veterans., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Newspaper clippings, 1925-1934
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series III: Patents, 1897-1925
  - Patents (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Theater materials, 1885-1920
  - Miscellaneous Theatre Material., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Theatre Programs, 1885-1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diary and Account Book, 1888-1894 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series V: Manuscripts
  - Trailing Geronimo., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A Story of the wild and woolly Southwest in the early eighties., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Southwest frontier - Section 1., undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Southwest frontier – Section 2., undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Southwest frontier (Clifton, AZ photos) – Section 3., undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Southwest frontier – Section 5 (i.e. 4)., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographs – Section 1-2., undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs – Section 3., undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs – Section 5 (i.e. 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photographs – Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Southwest frontier – Text (parts of Sec.1-3), undated (Box 3, Folder 1)